Guide to the John N. Paden papers, 1938-2010
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
John N. Paden papers
1938-2010
C0194
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
87.5 linear feet (133 boxes)
The collection includes periodicals, pamphlets, reports, conference proceedings, photographs, maps, printed ephemera, and manuscripts related to Sub-Saharan Africa, with particular emphasis on Nigeria, but embracing political and social history, biography, economics, sociology, languages, culture, and religions of the entire region. The role of Islam in the region is an important component. Documents are primarily in English but occasionally in German, French, Arabic, or Hausa.
Paden, John N.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by John N. Paden in 2011.
Biographical Information
Dr. John N. Paden is a Clarence Robinson Professor Emeritus of International Studies at George Mason University. He received his BA in philosophy from Occidental College, his MA in philosophy, politics, and economics from Oxford University as a Rhodes Scholar, and his PhD in politics from Harvard University.
Dr. Paden came to George Mason in 1987, and he taught comparative government, international development, and conflict resolution. He is a co-founder of the GMU graduate program in International Commerce and Policy (ICP). He is also co-founder and co-director of the GMU Center for Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (CAPEC), under the Office of the Provost. He has been involved in scholarly exchanges between the US and China and served as Director of the SPP/ICP summer graduate program in China, focusing on socio-economic changes and cross-cultural trade strategies. He also participated in the SPP/ICP summer trade programs in Oxford and Geneva. He helped develop undergraduate minors at GMU in Asia Pacific Studies, Islamic Studies, and Afro-American and African Studies. He has served as Director of African Studies at Northwestern University, Professor of Public Administration at Ahmadu Bello University (Zaria, Nigeria), and Dean, Faculty of Social and Management Sciences, at Bayero University (Kano, Nigeria).
Dr. Paden has also served on a senior level task force at the Brookings Institution on "US policy toward the Islamic world." Dr. Paden's work includes an extensive list of publications, including highly acclaimed textbooks about Africa. He retired from George Mason University in May 2017.
Scope and Content
The collection includes periodicals, pamphlets, reports, conference proceedings, photographs, maps, printed ephemera, and manuscripts related to Sub-Saharan Africa, with particular emphasis on Nigeria, but embracing political and social history, biography, economics, sociology, languages, culture, and religions of the entire region. The role of Islam in the region is an important component.
Series 1, Correspondence: Includes correspondence relating to book reviews, various publications, research projects, conferences, travel arrangements, publishing matters related to Dr. Paden's works, and letters of recommendation for students. Organized alphabetically by subject and then chronologically.
Series 2, Research: Published papers and documents, conference papers, and related materials. Research for Dr. Paden's dissertation is included and often separated by him into chapters and appendices, which include illustrations, maps, and tables. Major topics represented are politics, development, and economics; Hausa language and Hausa language education; Islam in Africa; African studies; Arabic literature; research for his book Black Africa; and broad information on Northern Nigeria. Materials are organized by subject and then chronologically. Materials from his former wife Ann are included and marked as such when known. Her research contains extensive information on family, childbirth, children, home health care and medicine, food, and issues specific to women. Series also includes index cards containing original research, most from the 1960s - 1970s. Materials are organized by type, subject, and then chronologically.
Series 3, Publications: Includes books, journals, newspapers, catalogs from publishing houses, and various ephemera. Contents relate mainly to Nigeria, but also included are items relating to other African nations as well as to the US and UK. Collection includes more than twenty different newspapers which were published in Nigeria, but primarily written in English. Major publications are the New Nigerian, Nigerian Citizen, and This Day. Newspapers range from the 1960s-2010. Magazines both political and popular are included. The series also contains travel-related publications from the 1970s, including airline schedules, tourist information, and many site-specific or event-specific brochures, some of which are interesting historical documents in their own right. The majority of travel brochures come from California, Chicago and Illinois, Michigan, Minnesota, and Texas, but some are from other regions of the US and overseas. Organized by subject and then chronologically.
Series 4: Maps. Includes maps of various African nations, primarily Nigeria. Organized by region and then chronologically. A greater quantity of maps may be found in Series 6, Oversize.
Series 5: Audio/Visual. Reel to reel audio tapes, audio cassette tapes, photographs, negatives. Audio recordings include radio interviews and other audio information relating to Nigeria in the 1960s. Photographs are primarily research-related images, the majority from Dr. Paden's trip to Africa in the 1960s, and include group portraits, images of Nigerian life, events, and royalty, and some personal family photographs dating from the 1930s. Slides are variously labeled by former wife Ann Paden as political rallies; crowd scenes; Hausa; Fulani; activities; Sallah; Malams; "Audo and the Padens;" images of Kano City, Morocco, Spain, and England; general landscape; friends; and the house in Nigeria which Dr. Paden and his former wife occupied. Not all of the subjects listed appear to be in the extant slide collection. Materials are organized by medium, then by subject, and then chronologically.
Series 6: Oversized. Maps, posters, a small amount of printed matter, one large photograph, and one large charcoal sketch. Includes maps up to wall size of Nigeria, other nations, and world regions. In addition to basic maps showing cities, states, and regions, series also includes maps illustrating demography, transportation, topography, concentration of religious groups, location of tribal areas, and other specialized information. Includes posters relating to politics, cultural ideals, and university education. A few posters reflect popular culture of the 1970s. Materials range from the 1950s-2000s. Materials are organized by medium, then by subject, and then chronologically.
Series 7: Realia. Includes a percussion instrument called a "yomkwo," or Nigerian raft zither, of the style made by the Birom (Berom) people of the Jos plateau. A yomkwo is a flat instrument made of reeds and grasses with a rattle attached to the back. Also included are eight Qur'an (Koran) boards, made of wood and other natural materials, in the style of the Hausa peoples. Six have Arabic writing on them. One is undecorated. Used for memorization of the Koran, often in conjunction with the drinking ink tradition. Materials are unidentified wood and ink. Paddle-shaped, about 8"-12"L x 6"-8"W. All realia is undated.
Arrangement
Series 1: Correspondence, 1971-1998 (Boxes 1-4)
Series 2: Research, 1950s-2010 (Boxes 4-85)
Series 3: Publications, 1959-2010 (Boxes 85-104, 111-129)
Series 4: Maps, 1949-1980s (Box 104)
Series 5: Audio/Visual, 1938-1985 (Boxes 105-109, 133)
Series 6: Oversize, 1949-1997 (110, 130, Map Case)
Series 7: Realia, undated (Boxes 131-132)
Related Materials
Special Collections and Archives also holds the papers of many other George Mason University professors, as well as materials pertaining to International Relations, including the, the, and the. Other collections containing photographs or slides of Nigeria include the, the, and the.
Bibliography
Index Terms
Persons:
Paden, John N.
Subjects:
Africa--Photographs.; Africa--Slides.; International Relations.; Nigeria.
Document Types:
Sound recordings.; Negatives.; Photographs.
Contents List
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1960-2005; (3.5 boxes)
  Includes various types of correspondence relating to book reviews, publications, research projects, travel arrangements, letters of recommendation, and some few personal matters. Organized alphabetically by subject and then chronologically.
  - ASA Convention, October 31-November 3, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Chairing the panel on ethnicity.
  - Academic contacts, June 9, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Academic, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Includes letters of recommendation.
  - Academic, career, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adam, Abdurraham, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Regarding admissions to Northwestern.
  - Adamu, Harun, March 25-October 14, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Letter of appointment as Dean of Social Sciences at Ahmadu Bello University.
  - African Studies Association, November 17, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ahmadu Bello-Kamrany, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ahmadu Bello University, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Aidoo, Alexander Kwame, October 6, 1971-January 20, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bayreuth, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Identity in Africa program.
  - Bishop, Vaughn, June 18-August 24, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Black Africa, January 31, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - CSIS, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cambridge University Press, November 25, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Coen, Robert, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Course development.
  - Cohen, Dr. Abner, July 3-August 28, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Divorce and career, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Exchange of students, China, April 5, 1979, January 1, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ferguson, Phyllis, April 4, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Letter of recommendation and supporting material.
  - GMU related, 1982-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hausa Language Teacher, March 20-May 30, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Seeking replacement teacher at Northwestern.
  - ICPR/Ann Arbor, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - INTL 501-Book orders, December 1, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - International Relations, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    National Endowment for the Humanities.
  - James, Jack, September, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Kalamazoo College, September 1979-April 1980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Maguire, Andy, May-June, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Relates to Maguire's political campaign.
  - Manuscript reviews, May 17-August 9, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Mayer, Lucille, November 21, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - McCaskie, Thomas and Sue, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Metuge, Wang, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mohammed, Abdullahi, September 6, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - National Universities Commission, November 2009 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Nigeria travel plans, December 31, 1969-January 26, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Nigeria trip, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Nigerian conference, February-April 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - North Carolina symposium, January-April 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Afro-Asian World in Transition.
  - Northwestern, April 4, 1967-February 6, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Northwestern, March 25, 1969-June 20, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Northwestern, April 30, 1980-October 14, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - PAS, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - PAS, October-November 1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    AAI Program.
  - Paden, Ann, January 22, 1964-August 2, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Paden, Ann, letters to family, January 22, 1964-August 2, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Paden, Bill, 1969-1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Publishing arrangements, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Includes extensive exchanges with University of California Press.
  - Publishing arrangements, 1978, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Rosenblum, Oscar, August 11, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Sanders, Jim, April, October 1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Student related, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - US-China-African studies exchange, October-November 1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - University of Ibadan, September 20, October 18, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Strife at the university.
  - Various, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Various, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Various, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Various, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Various, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Various, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Folder 1 of 2.
  - Various, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Folder 2 of 2.
  - Various, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Various, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Various, 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - WMRT, December, 1977-May 1, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Wisconsin, October 1995-April 1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Zahradeen/Adams, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Series 2: Research, 1950s-2007; (81 boxes)
  Published papers and documents, conference papers, and related materials. Research for Dr. Paden's dissertation is included and often separated by him into chapters and appendices, which include illustrations and tables. Major topics represented are politics, development, and economics; Hausa language and Hausa language education; Islam in Africa; African studies; Arabic literature; research for his book Black Africa; and broad information on Northern Nigeria. Materials are organized by type, subject, and then chronologically.
  - ANIP working papers, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Folder 1 of 4. Identified by Dr. Paden. Interior identifies contents of folder as "Book vol II / Elite analysis / draft."
  - ANIP working papers, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Folder 2 of 4. "Instability and National Integration in Thirty-Two Independent African States: A Step-Wise Discriminant Function Analysis." Contains internal working papers numbers 5-10, 12.
  - ANIP working papers, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Folder 3 of 4. "Instability and National Integration in Thirty-Two Independent African States: A Step-Wise Discriminant Function Analysis." Contains internal working papers numbers 15-19.
  - ANIP working papers, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Folder 4 of 4. "Instability and National Integration in Thirty-Two Independent African States: A Step-Wise Discriminant Function Analysis." Contains internal working papers numbers 21-23, 26.
  - APSA, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    "Modernization, Stability, and National Integration in Africa" by John N. Paden.
  - APSA meeting, September 8-12, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Folder 1 of 3. Meeting of the American Political Science Association in Los Angeles.
  - APSA meeting, September 8-12, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Folder 2 of 3. Meeting of the American Political Science Association in Los Angeles.
  - APSA meeting, September 8-12, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Folder 3 of 3. Meeting of the American Political Science Association in Los Angeles.
  - ASA annual meeting, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Published in 1973 by the Institute of International Studies, University of South Carolina.
  - ASA careers, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Notes on possible career paths for African Studies students.
  - ASA Convention, October 31-November 3, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Folder 1 of 3. African Studies Association meeting. Includes correspondence and related materials.
  - ASA Convention, October 31-November 3, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Folder 2 of 3. African Studies Association meeting. Includes correspondence and related materials.
  - ASA Convention, October 31-November 3, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Folder 3 of 3. African Studies Association meeting. Includes correspondence and related materials.
  - ASA, October 1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Includes contact information.
  - ASA, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Includes printed literature and book lists.
  - ASA, October 21-24, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Thirteenth annual meeting.
  - Abba, Aminu Akbar-bibliography, June 1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Abdullahi Bn. Fodio conference, March 8-11, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Folder 1 of 2. Copies of multiple papers for presentation in Sokoto.
  - Abdullahi Bn. Fodio conference, March 8-11, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Folder 2 of 2. Copies of multiple papers for presentation in Sokoto.
  - Abdullahi Bayero College/Ahmadu Bello, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Abdullahi Bayero University College, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Abuja update, February 23, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Academic, May 20, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    "The Conflict between National and Supra-National Loyalties in the Political Thought of French-Speaking West Africa," by John N. Paden for GOVT 295: Nationalism
  - An Account of the Paden Collection of Arabic Materials, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - An Account of the Paden Collection of Arabic Materials, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Addresses, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Adler court case, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    James E. Adler v. The Federal Republic of Nigeria.
  - Africa-field notes, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Original field notes from 1960s trip to Nigeria. See also note cards in Boxes 80-83.
  - Africa Report 1971-ASA and related, July 1968-October 1969 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - African Bibliographies, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - African Bibliographies, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Africa economics and management, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - African Experiences Volume II, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Bibliographic references.
  - African history, 1963-1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - African studies, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Presentation papers.
  - African studies, 1970s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - African Studies Association 22nd Annual Meeting, October 31-November 3, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Los Angeles.
  - African Studies, Northwestern, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - African Studies symposium, April 2-3, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Folder 1 of 3.
  - African Studies symposium, April 2-3, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Folder 2 of 3.
  - African Studies symposium, April 2-3, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Folder 3 of 3.
  - Agency for International Development, September 12, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Final draft. A long range plan defining alternative strategies for the development of the Sahel-Sudan Zones. Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Center for Policy Alternatives.
  - Agriculture and development, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture-Report to the Board of Governors, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Folder 1 of 2. Institute for Agricultural Research, Ahmadu Bello University.
  - Agriculture-Report to the Board of Governors, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Folder 2 of 2. Institute for Agricultural Research, Ahmadu Bello University.
  - Ahmadu Bello-Institute of Administration, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Ahmadu Bello University, 1964, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Contains article by John N. Paden, "Kano Hausa Poetry: Reply."
  - Ahmadu Bello University, July 1, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Regulations governing the conditions of appointment of senior staff of Ahmadu Bello University.
  - Ahmadu Bello University, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Ahmadu Bello University, June 1982 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Ahmadu Bello University, ADC-Environmental Survey, March 1976 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Ahmadu Bello University, Abuja proposal, 1980s (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Ahmadu University, Sokoto seminar, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Ahmadu University, Sokoto seminar, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Al-Ahram Centre for Political and Strategic Studies, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Aliyu, Dr. A.Y., 1983 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Aluor, Lucy Zaiyol Abagu, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Imposition of Native Administration and the Evolution of Chieftancy among the Tiv.
  - American Data Research at Northwestern, January 1974 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - American Political Science Association Conference, September 7-11, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Folder 1 of 4.
  - American Political Science Association Conference, September 7-11, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Folder 2 of 4.
  - American Political Science Association Conference, September 7-11, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Folder 3 of 4.
  - American Political Science Association Conference, September 7-11, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Folder 4 of 4.
  - Americans for Democracy in Africa, May 5, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Ames, David, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 2)
    A Sociocultural View of Hausa Musical Activity.
  - Amulet material, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Folder 1 of 6. Written charms, drinking ink, folk remedies.
  - Amulet material, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Folder 2 of 6. Written charms, drinking ink, folk remedies.
  - Amulet material, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Folder 3 of 6. Written charms, drinking ink, folk remedies.
  - Amulet material, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Folder 4 of 6. Written charms, drinking ink, folk remedies.
  - Amulet material, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Folder 5 of 6. Written charms, drinking ink, folk remedies.
  - Amulet material, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Folder 6 of 6. Written charms, drinking ink, folk remedies.
  - Appendices, bibliographies, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Appendices, bibliographies, addenda, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Appendix II, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Appendix II, 1970s (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Appendix II, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Appendix II, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Appendix II, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Appendix IV, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Appendix XXVIII, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Arabic, booklet, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Contains written material and the handmade paper book cover which originally housed it.
  - Arabic, booklet, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Arabic, booklet-"not poetry", undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Arabic booklets, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Arabic documents from JOS museum, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Arabic language, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Arabic, "faith and morality" booklet, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Arabic notes, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Arabic notes, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Arabic notes, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Arabic notes, 1960s (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Arabic, "prayer, poetry," booklet, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Arabic, "prayer, poetry. 5," booklet, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Arabic, "prayer, poetry, 30," booklet, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Arabic, "prayer, poetry, 40," booklet, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Arabic, "prayer, poetry, 55," booklet, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Arabic, "prayer, poetry, 56," booklet, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Arabic, "prayer, poetry, 62," booklet, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Arabic religion, booklet, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Association of African Studies Programs, April 4-6, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Attracting Capital to Africa Summit, April 25-27, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Houston, TX. Includes list of confirmed attendees.
  - Badamaze genealogy, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Notes on marriage and relationships.
  - Background information and sources, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Background material on the African Economic Policy Initiative, January-February, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Baker, Pauline, January 1983 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    Obstacles to Private Sector Activities in Africa
  - Bakin Ruwa questionnaire - research tool, Ann Paden, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Bakin Ruwa questionnaire - research tool, Ann Paden, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Bakin Ruwa questionnaire - research tool, Ann Paden, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Bako, Augustine Kurah. Bibliography, June 1984 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Bayero University, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Prospectus, telephone directory.
  - Biafra, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    News articles and scholarly work.
  - Bibliographies, 1960s (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Bibliographies, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 4)